MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF IV

Summary

Award-winning professional with a Master's degree in IT Management who leverages technical expertise and exceptional leadership skills to deliver creative solutions for end-users and strategic business needs. Experience includes leading high-performing multi-disciplinary teams from product development through successful product launches.

Experience

Bickford Senior Living

• Exceptional interpersonal communication.

Member of Technical Staff IV

June 2011 to Current Sonora Quest Laboratories i1/4 Marion, AZ

- Slashed wholesale maintenance and inventory costs by over \$18.7 million in 2015 by leading multiple cross-functional teams designing and testing of strategic Gigabit Passive Optical Network (GPON) products.
- These savings were accomplished by a new process migrating SES and DS1 circuits from copper facilities to more robust and reliable GPON network infrastructure.
- Greatly expanded revenue and averted inventory exhaust potential through customer reactive migration of retail services by leading the effort to move end-customers services from vendor retired terminals to more advanced network terminals.
- This solution allowed for the delivery of higher speed/higher priced services on the new terminals and recovery of spare parts for the terminals at exhaust.
- Shortened production delivery times by leading initiatives virtualizing key services utilizing ITKO LISA products.
- Virtualization gave teams the ability to test independently of other applications who had not yet delivered code for end-to-end application flows thus moving defect detection left in the testing cycle.
- Developed strategic relationships with clients and users to drive product adoption by performing as client liaison to drive understanding of business operations within the IT organization.
- Established continuous testing by transitioning the Systems Integration Testing organization from a waterfall SDLC to an agile method incorporating a DevOps model.
- Established project Level of Effort (LOE) as well as assigning resources based on skill-sets needed for projects.
- Created and managed budget for team of 10 people totaling over \$1 million.
- Effectively mentored and trained new employees as a product and technical SME, as well as aiding them in forging new relationships with business partners to increase team productivity.

Lead Software Tester

February 2004 to June 2011 Ajilon Consulting i $\frac{1}{4}$ Phoenix , STATE

- Lead the User Acceptance Test ramp up and rollout of Verion's high speed FiOS network.
- This continued through the application lifecycle to legacy status.
- Established self as SME of FiOS products and single point of contact for production user support in real time.
- Worked with users, system architects, developers, and requirements team to formulate create business IT solutions and translate them into actionable test plans with clear objectives and metrics.
- Coordinated fiber optic live lab inventory setup and testing across multiple regions of the country to provide customers with the highest quality of service activation and customer downtime.
- Highly engaged member of Provisioning Change Control Board planning release cycles with Go/No Go authority.

Senior Computer Operator

September 2000 to February 2004 Minyard's Food Stores il/4 City, STATE

- Maintained computer operations equipment and peripheral devices to guarantee up-to-date pricing for each of 82 store locations.
- Operated IBM iSeries, AS/400e, eServer iSeries/400 and custom programs to facilitate continuous business function.
- Facilitated vendor communication and automated purchasing through corporate servers.
- Generated reporting daily metrics for managers and executives.
- Worked directly with Operations Manager to lead key objectives to completion by team members throughout day and night shifts.

Education

 $Masters\ of\ Science: Information\ Technology\ Management\ ,\ December\ 2014\ Western\ Governor's\ University\ i'\slash\ City\ ,\ State\ Information\ Technology\ Management$

Bachelor of Applied Arts and Sciences: May 2011 Texas A&M University i1/4 City, State

Certifications

Agile methodologies Project management Systems Development Life Cycle (SDLC) Advanced understanding of Microsoft Project Data analysis Strategic planning

Additional Information

Awards Verizon CIO Spotlight Award for Leadership June 2015 Verizon Project Manager Organization Personal Commitment Award
February 2015 Verizon Executive Director Spotlight Award for Personal Commitment November 2014 Verizon CIO Spotlight Award for
Customer Excellence October 2014

Skills

Agile, AS/400, budget, business operations, interpersonal communication, computer operations, clients, client liaison, Data analysis, delivery, designing, functional, IBM, inventory, Microsoft Project, migration, LISA, Network, pricing, Project management, purchasing, quality, real time, reporting, retail, SDLC, servers, strategic, Strategic planning, Systems Development, Systems Integration, user support